Joseph DeWoody

Fort Worth, Texas, United States



linkedin.com/in/josephdewoody



jpd@clearforkroyalty.com



(817) 370-1322

Summary

Joseph DeWoody is the CEO of Valor Mineral Management. Joseph is an experienced leader with a demonstrated history of working in oil and gas mineral rights and royalty acquisition and management. Throughout his time in the industry he has acquired and managed oil and gas interests in over 10,000 wells throughout 27 States. Joseph has experience in all aspects of oil and gas exploration, production, development and management. Joseph DeWoody is a Certified Mineral Manager and a Certified Professional Landman.

Predictive Index: Maverick Culture Index: Enterpriser

CliftonStrengths: Achiever, Competition, Belief, Context, Learner

Myers-Briggs: ESTJ

Wealth Dynamics: Creator

Experience



CEO / CTO

Valor Mineral Management Feb 2020 - Present (7 months +)



CEO / CTO

mineral.tech

Feb 2020 - Present (7 months +)

GER Partner

Clear Fork Royalty

Feb 2020 - Present (7 months +)



Member Member

Forbes Technology Council

2020 - Present (8 months +)



(≰) Director

The Texas Lyceum

Jan 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months +)



National Association of Royalty Owners - Texas

Jul 2016 - Present (4 years 2 months +)



National Stripper Well Association

Oct 2013 - Present (6 years 11 months +)



Valor Mineral Management

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020 (1 year 2 months)

President

Clear Fork Royalty

Jan 2010 - Feb 2020 (10 years 2 months)

Producer

Tennessee Whiskey: The Dean Dillon Story

2017 - 2017 (1 year)

A legend in Nashville, Dean Dillon finally comes out of the shadows and shares his music, his life, and the stories behind the hits in this honest film about a man responsible for songs that shaped an era. Dean discusses his career, the stories behind the hits and his collaboration with such stars as George Strait, Kenny Chesney and Toby Keith.

Appointed Board Member

Apr 2013 - Dec 2016 (3 years 9 months)

Appointed by Texas Governor Rick Perry. The Texas Board of Professional Geoscientists (TBPG) was created in 2001 by Senate Bill 405 in the 77th Legislature. Senate Bill 405, also known as the Texas Geoscience Practice Act, became Texas Occupations Code 1002. Officially becoming effective on September 1, 2003, TOC 1002 is the governing statute by which the TBPG operates. The Texas Geoscience Practice Act is the basis for all agency rules, policies and procedures. The TBPG is governed by a nine-member Board, all appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Board consists of six Professional Geoscientists and three public members, which serve staggered six-year terms.

Director

Texas Alliance of Energy Producers

Jan 2013 - Dec 2015 (3 years)

Education

Baylor University - Hankamer School of Business

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.)

Baylor University

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Entrepreneurship and Real Estate

The University of Texas at Austin

Full-Stack Web Development

Columbia Business School

Python for Managers

Harvard Business School Online
CORe

Southwest Christian School

Licenses & Certifications

Certified Professional Landman - AAPL - American Association of Professional Landmen

☐ Certified Mineral Manager - National Association of Royalty Owners

- Certified Professional Lease and Title Analyst National Association of Lease and Title Analysts
- **Foundation Certified** ZURB

Honors & Awards

- Better Business Bureau Torch Award for Ethics Better Business Bureau
- Greater Tarrant Business Ethics Award Fort Worth Chamber of Commerce
- Texas Top Producer Top Landman in Texas TIPRO / Texas Monthly Magazine
- 20 under 40 in Exploration and Production Oil & Gas Investor Magazine

 Presented by Hart Energy to those who further the goals of their organizations and the industry through their initiative, intelligence and persistence.
- 📕 Who's Who in Energy Dallas Business Journal
- **40 under 40** Fort Worth Business Press
- Future 40 Award Maverick PAC
- Distinguished Alumni Southwest Christian School

Skills

Energy Industry • Natural Gas • Oil & Gas Industry • Mergers & Acquisitions • Petroleum • Energy • Due Diligence • Entrepreneurship • Mineral Rights • Joint Ventures